<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<root>
  <title>香港示威与中国经济（HK Protest and the Chinese Economy)</title>
  <time>(2014-10-04 09:00:00)</time>
  <content>应英国The Conversation网站邀请， 特写下面的文章。 题目为Hong Kong Protest and the Chinese Economy. 摘要：许多香港人不满该地区领导人的产生方式，在中环大规模示威的人大多是大学生。他们对中国大陆毫不了解，更不想起了解。尽管北京坚持港人治港和一国两制原则，这些年轻人还是要求“民主”，而实现民主的唯一形式就是“一人一票”。 对大陆人来说，香港人该干嘛干嘛，与我无关。而北京却不这样认为，她要求特首忠于国家和共产党。这就是矛盾所在。尽管在英国殖民时代，所有28任港督，都是英国国王或女皇直接任命的英国人，那时候，香港人都是乖乖仔。然而，回归以后，香港人已经不满足于“港人治港”的基本原则，并开始不断的“闹事”，而且 越来越凶。 示威者到底想干什么？是要民主吗？如果问题没有那么简单，而是有其它不可告人的目的，那么，示威的结果也许会适得其反，影响真正民主的进程。 中国目前最关心的是大陆的经济增长和社会发展。在经济从外延型向内生型转变的过程中，增长速度放慢了，从原来的10%下降到7.5%。 速度放慢不是问题，只要就业得到保障就还好。问题在于，速度慢质量有没有提高？而经济增长质量提高的标志是高端制造、高增加值服务和快速的内陆地区增长。 中国在这些方面已经取得一些成功。不过，2014年的形势依然严重。增长乏力，房地产疲软，外资流入和出口首次出现负增长。 香港的示威也许是大陆经济发展挑战的折射。不过，香港对大陆的重要性已经发生根本性的改变，港人可能还没有意识到这一点。 就在香港的边界，深圳干的非常好。往北看，珠三角已经不需要香港的帮助就能自身发展了。如果说上世纪中国快速发展离不开香港的帮助的话，那么，到了本世纪，香港的发展已经离不开大陆的资本和游客了。 正因如此，北京没有必要对香港的示威感到紧张，更没有必要做出太快的让步。 不管如何，香港短期的示威和国内的经济转型困难，都不会阻碍中国长期发展的决心。 Hong Kong Protest and the Chinese Economy Obviously, many Hong Kongers are not happy with the way their territory has been governed after it was returned to China since 1997. The recent protest has escalated to such a scale that the central authority has leveled it as “illegal” mass demonstration, which is totally forbidden in the mainland. In the 1980s, Mrs Margaret Thatcher and Mr Deng Xiaoling both agreed to hand over Hong Kong to China under the basic principle of “one country, two systems”. Since 1997, Hong Kong has enjoyed a status of Special Administration Region (SAR), which is distinctively different from any of the 31 province-level administrative units in mainland China. Hong Kong has its own financial, business and press autonomy, and its people are allowed to do many things that mainlanders are strictly prohibited to do, including prolonged protests and occupations in city centres. What do the demonstrators want? The vast majority of them are college students, who have little understanding of, or no intention to understand, mainland China, let alone its people and the communist party. These young people have been educated to believe that “democracy” is the only way that Hong Kong will prosper and “one person one vote” is the only solution for realizing the goal. From the mainlanders’ prospective, whatever happens in Hong Kong has nothing to do with them, as long as Hong Kong is a part of their motherland. But this is not the view of the ruling party, who wishes to control Hong Kong in its own way, that is, whoever is the governor, he or she must be loyal to the central state and the party. As a result, all the past and the current governors have been largely “hand-picked” by Beijing, although the principle of “Hong Kongers Governing Hong Kong” has been upheld. This is different from the British colonial period when all the 28 Hong Kong governors were British and directly appointed by the British monarchs. However, many Hong Kongers, especially the youngsters, demand the current governor to step down and to use the “one person one vote system” to elect future governors. Whether and when the central government will vow to demonstrators’ demand is unknown. What we do know is that Beijing must have been irritated by the demonstrators without an effective and quick solution to the problem. The protestors may wish for “quick democracy”, but their mainland counterparts and the central authority may interpret their emotion and motivation rather differently. Do they really just demand democracy? Or are they using democracy as an excuse to make trouble in Hong Kong? Or are some of the protestors agitated and supported by western powers to create conflicts between Hong Kong and the mainland for some hidden political and ideological agenda? If the central authority considers that democracy is used as a tool to harm China’s interest, then the final effect of the protest could be counterproductive in the process of democratic development in Hong Kong. One may have a good reason to believe that the unstable situation in Hong Kong must have had an adverse impact on China’s economic growth and development. However, one needs not overstate the importance of Hong Kong nowadays in comparison with its past influence on the mainland. On Hong Kong’s border, the city of Shenzhen has been doing spectacularly well. Northward, the Zhujiang River Delta can now prosper by itself without Hong Kong’s help. The relative importance of Hong Kong to the mainland has changed over time. In the 1980s and 1990’s, China could not develop fast without Hong Kong’s capital and expertise, today, Hong Kong cannot prosper without China’s investment and tourism. What does this mean? It means that the mainland, especially the government are not desperate to meet Hong Kongers’ demand which may be considered by the former as “unreasonable”, or “trouble-making”. The overwhelming top priority of the central government is economic growth and social development. The year 2014 is probably the most challenging year for China in a decade. As the country has turned its attention away from extensive growth to intensive internal development, the growth rate of gross domestic product has slowed down to merely 7.5%, compared to an average growth rate of nearly 10% for more than twenty years before the world financial crisis. Furthermore, foreign direct investments and exports have experienced negative growth for the first time in many years, in sharp contrast to the over 10%, or even more than 20% annual growth in the past. Slow growth is not a real problem itself as long as it can still generate sufficient employment. The real problem is whether slow growth can also improve China’s growth quality, which depends on the development of high-tech industries, high value-added services, and faster growth in the less developed regions. There are signs that China has made some good progress in that direction, but the current situation is not at all rosy. The housing industry has been one of the most important industries in China for its high growth, but market distortion, corruption and government land sales policies have blown the market into an uncontrollable bubble. On the one hand, house prices are too high for the low income people. On the other hand, the rich and middle-class people have hoarded tens of millions of houses unoccupied. The waste and concentration of resources in one sector must have diluted and delayed investments in others. Unfortunately, instead of trying to contain the housing bubble, the central bank has allowed people to take their first mortgages with a 30% discount of interest payments, irrespective of the number of houses they have bought. The sudden and unexpected policy shift implies that China must have faced tough challenges to meet its economic growth target this year without stimulating the foamy housing market again. The trouble in Hong Kong may just echo the internal economic challenges. However, the new government’s anti-corruption efforts have received popular support from the people, and any short term political unrest in Hong Kong and economic stress in the mainland may not change the course of the country’s long term development determination.</content>
</root>
